PROFESSOR: In this video, we're going to begin our discussion of global program optimization.
教授：在这段视频中，我们将开始讨论全球程序优化。
And it turns out that, in order to talk about global optimization, there's another topic
事实证明，为了谈论全局优化，还有另一个主题
that we have to deal with first known as data flow analysis.
我们首先要处理的是数据流分析。
Let's begin by reviewing the simple basic-block optimizations. In particular, constant propagation
让我们首先回顾一下简单的基本挡路优化。具体地说，恒定传播
and dead code elimination. So here's a little piece of code. And you'll notice that there's
和死码消除。这里有一小段代码。你会注意到这里有
an assignment of a constant X. And we know from our lecture in local optimizations that
一个常数X的赋值，我们从我们的课程“局部优化”中了解到
that constant assignment could be propagated forward to the uses of X. If the basic block
这个常量赋值可以被转发给X的用法。如果基本的挡路
is in single assignment form, this is particularly easy to do. And then if the value of X here
是以单一作业形式进行的，这特别容易做到。如果这里X的值
is not used anyplace else in the program, that statement is dead and can be deleted.
不在程序中的任何其他地方使用，则该语句已失效，可以删除。
So here's a simple example over a basic block combining constant propagation and dead code
因此，这里有一个简单的示例，它基于结合了常量传播和死代码的基本挡路
elimination.
淘汰赛。
Now, these optimizations can be extended to an entire control-flow graph. So here now
现在，这些优化可以扩展到整个控制流图。所以现在在这里
we have a nontrivial control-flow graph. Remember, a control-flow graph is a graph of basic blocks
我们有一个非常重要的控制流图。请记住，控制流图是基本块的图
where the nodes are the basic blocks and the edges show the transfers of control between
其中节点是基本块，而边表示控制在
basic blocks. And so this first basic block here has a testament, an if statement. And
基本块。所以这里的第一个基本挡路有一个证明，一个if语句。和
it'll go to one basic block if the test is true. Into a different basic block if the
如果测试是真的，就给一个基本的挡路。转换为不同的基本挡路，如果
test is false.
测试为假。
Now, in this control-flow graph, we can observe that X is assigned a constant. And then down
现在，在这个控制流图中，我们可以观察到X被分配了一个常量。然后向下
here, there are uses of X. And, in fact, in this particular case, it is going to be safe
在这里，有X的用法。事实上，在这种情况下，它将是安全的
to replace this use of X by the constant 3. So just like we propagated constants in a
将X的这种用法替换为常量3。因此，就像我们在
single basic block, we can also, at least in some circumstances, propagate constants
单一的基本挡路，我们还可以，至少在某些情况下，传播常量
across entire control-flow graphs.
跨越整个控制流图。
Now, it turns out that there are some situations in which it's not safe to propagate constants.
现在，事实证明，在某些情况下传播常量是不安全的。
So here again let's observe that we have an assignment of X, an assignment of a constant
在这里，让我们再次观察一下，我们有一个X的赋值，一个常量的赋值
X, and down here we have a use of X. But we cannot replace this X here by 3. And why is
在这下面我们有X的用法，但是我们不能用3来代替这个X，为什么呢？
that? Well, that's because over here, we have another assignment X where X gets the value
那?嗯，那是因为在这里，我们有另一个赋值X，其中X得到值
4.
And the interesting thing about this example is that notice that X is only assigned constants.
这个例子的有趣之处在于，请注意，X只分配了常量。
So X is assigned a constant here, and X is assigned a constant here, but this value of
所以X在这里被赋值为常量，X在这里被赋值为常量，但是
X down here is not known. We don't know which constant it's going to be, because if we come
这里的X是未知的。我们不知道它会是哪个常数，因为如果我们来
from this path in the execution, then X will be 4. And if we come from this path, the value
在执行过程中，从这条路径开始，X将是4。如果我们从这条路径开始，则值
of X will be 3. And so we can't replace x here by either one of those values, and it's
将会是3，所以我们不能用这两个值中的任何一个来代替这里的x，它是
not safe in this case to propagate constants to this use of X.
在这种情况下，将常量传播到X的此用法是不安全的。
And so the question then is, how do we know when it is OK to globally propagate constants?
那么问题就来了，我们怎么知道什么时候可以全局传播常量呢？
Now, for constant propagation, it turns out there's a simple criteria. To replace a use
现在，对于恒定的传播，结果是有一个简单的标准。要替换使用，请执行以下操作
of x by a constant k, we have to know the following fact that on every path to the use
x乘以常数k，我们必须知道以下事实，即在使用的每条路径上
of x. So every path that leads to the use of x, the last assignment that x is, x is
所以每条通向x使用的路径，x的最后一个赋值，x是
equal to k. So every single path that goes to x-- and this make sense, I think, intuitively--
等于k。所以通向x的每一条路径--我认为，直觉上讲，这是有意义的--
we must have assigned a constant x along that path. And that must, in fact, be the last
我们一定是沿着那条路径分配了一个常数x。事实上，这肯定是最后一次
assignment to x on each path.
为每条路径上的x赋值。
Let's take a look at our example again, and I'll switch colors here. So here we have the
让我们再看看我们的示例，我将在这里切换颜色。所以我们在这里看到了
assignment X equals 3, and down here we have the use of X. And now what we need to do is
赋值X等于3，下面我们有X的用法，现在我们需要做的是
we need to check, in order to replace this X by 3, that on every path it arrives at this
我们需要检查，为了将这个X替换为3，在它到达的每条路径上
X. It reaches this X that X is assigned 3 along that path. Well, there are only two
到达这个X，X沿着那条路径被指定为3。嗯，只有两个
paths. There's this path, and there's this path. And it's easy to see that this assignment
路径。有这条路，也有这条路。很容易看出，这项任务
is on both of those paths. And therefore the last assignment done on both paths, on all
都在这两条路上。因此，在两条路径上完成的最后一次赋值是在所有
paths, is X equals 3. And therefore we can replace this X by 3.
路径，是X等于3，因此我们可以用3代替这个X。
In contrast, with this use of X in this example, we have a path here where X is assigned 3,
相反，在本例中使用X的情况下，我们这里有一条路径，其中X被指定为3，
and we have a path here that reaches along this path. Let me draw the whole path, actually.
我们这里有一条沿着这条路延伸的小路。实际上，让我画出整个路线。
And along this path, the last assignment to X is 4, and so we cannot propagate any constant
沿着这条路径，X的最后一个赋值是4，所以我们不能传播任何常量
value to this use of X.
这种使用X的价值。
In general, the correctness condition that a variable is assigned the same constant to
一般而言，变量被赋予相同常量的正确性条件
lock all paths to a use of that variable is not that easy to check, because 'quot;all paths'quot;
锁定使用该变量的所有路径并不那么容易检查，因为“所有路径”
includes paths that go around loops as well as paths that go through conditionals, as
包括绕过循环的路径以及通过条件条件的路径，如
we saw in the example. So checking these conditions is done through a family of techniques called
我们在示例中看到。因此，检查这些条件是通过一系列称为
'quot;global dataflow analysis,'quot; and it's designed specifically to check conditions like this.
“全球数据流分析”，它是专门为检查这样的条件而设计的。
And essentially, global dataflow analysis is called 'quot;global'quot; because it requires an
从本质上讲，全局数据流分析被称为“全局”，因为它需要
analysis of the entire control-flow graph.
分析整个控制流图。
Stepping back for a moment, there are many global optimization tasks that we would like
退一步说，我们希望有许多全局优化任务
a compiler to perform. A constant propagation, global constant propagation, is just one of
要执行的编译器。常量传播，全局常量传播，只是
those. Now, it turns out that all of these global optimization problems share several
那些。现在，事实证明，所有这些全局优化问题都有几个共同点
common traits. So first of all, the optimization always depends on knowing some property X
共同的特点。所以首先，优化总是依赖于知道一些属性X
at a particular point in the program. So we want to know some piece of very local information.
在程序中的特定时间点。所以我们想知道一些非常地方性的信息。
So, for example, is X at a particular point in the program guaranteed to be a constant?
那么，例如，程序中某一特定点的X是否保证为常量？
OK? That's the property for a constant propagation.
好的?这就是常量传播的性质。
Now, however, even though we want to know some local fact, something that's specific
然而，现在，尽管我们想知道一些当地的事实，一些具体的事情
to a particular point in the program, proving this fact requires knowledge of the entire
对于程序中的某个特定点，要证明这一事实需要了解整个
program, so at least the entire control-flow graph. So as we saw in the case of constant
程序，因此至少是整个控制流图。因此，正如我们在常量情况下看到的那样
propagation, to figure out whether X is a constant at a particular point in the program
传播，以确定X是否为程序中特定点的常量
requires reasoning about all the paths that lead to that statement. And that is a global
需要对通向该语句的所有路径进行推理。这是一个全球性的
property. So when you think about all-paths, that could be a path from the entry point
财产。因此，当您考虑所有路径时，这可能是从入口点开始的路径
of the method all the way through loops and across conditionals to the particular statement.
方法的所有过程，通过循环并跨越特定语句的条件。
So, in general, that's a very hard problem to solve. And for certain kinds of questions,
所以，总的来说，这是一个很难解决的问题。对于某些类型的问题，
it's really extremely expensive to solve it exactly. The thing that saves us is that it
准确地解决这个问题真的非常昂贵。拯救我们的是它
is OK always to be conservative. So typically for these optimizations-- and if we want to
总是保守是可以的。所以通常情况下，对于这些优化--如果我们想
know some property X-- then what we really want to know is either X is definitely true--
知道一些属性X--那么我们真正想知道的是，要么X绝对是真的--
So if we say that the property is true, then we have to be right. We can't make a mistake.
因此，如果我们说属性是真实的，那么我们就必须是正确的。我们不能犯错误。
But it is always OK to say that you don't know. So it's OK to give up and say we don't
但是说你不知道总是可以的。所以放弃也没关系，说我们不会
know whether the property holds or not. Because of the worst case, we just don't do the optimization.
知道房产是否保有。因为最坏的情况，我们就是不做优化。
If we can't establish the conditions that would mean it was definitely correct to the
如果我们不能确定条件，那就意味着它肯定是正确的
optimizations, then we want to play it safe and not do the optimization.
优化，那么我们希望稳妥行事，不做优化。
So having approximate techniques or techniques that don't always give the correct answer
因此，拥有近似的技术或技术并不总是能给出正确的答案
to the questions that we wanted to ask is OK as long as we are always right when we
对我们想问的问题的回答是可以的，只要我们总是对的
say that the property holds and otherwise we just say that we don't know whether the
假设该属性保持不变，否则我们只会说我们不知道
property holds or not.
属性是否有效。
To sum up, global dataflow analysis is a standard technique or family of techniques for solving
总而言之，全局数据流分析是解决以下问题的标准技术或技术系列
problems with the characteristics that we just discussed. And global constant propagation
与我们刚才讨论的特征有关的问题。和全局恒定传播
is one example of an optimization that requires global dataflow analysis. And in the next
是需要全局数据流分析的优化的一个示例。在接下来的时间里
several videos, we'll be looking at global constant propagation and another dataflow
几个视频，我们将看到全局常量传播和另一个数据流
analysis in more detail.
更详细的分析。